kingstoncommunications.com 2014-04-15

# KC - Legal

## Privacy Policy

Thank you for visiting the KC website, which is part of the KCOM Group PLC. KCOM Group and its companies take the privacy of your information very seriously. We aim to meet current internet best practice. Our services are designed to give you the information that you want to receive. Our privacy policy below explains how we will collect and use the information you give us.

This privacy policy is published by KCOM Group PLC ("KCOM" or " we" or " us"). KCOM Group is a company registered in England under number 2150618 at 37 Carr Lane, Hull, East Yorkshire, HU1 3RE ("KCOM Group Address").

**Contents**

  * Our approach
  * Information collection 
  * Use of information we collect
  * Who may process data
  * Security measures
  * Cookies
  * Access and changes to your personal information
  * Changes to this policy
  * Enquiries
  * Managing your contact with KC

##  1\. OUR APPROACH

KC takes the privacy of its users seriously. Generally, you can browse through our website without giving us any information about yourself (including your email address). When we do need your personal information to provide services that you request or when you choose to provide us with your personal information, this policy describes how we collect and use your personal information.

If we decide to change our privacy policy for this website, we will post those changes here so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information and whether we will disclose it to anyone.

>back to top

##  2\. INFORMATION COLLECTION

We collect personal information (such as your name, email address and any other details you provide to us that identifies you as an individual) from you when you submit a request for information or when you submit your details for any other reason. Personal information will only be collected with your consent.

When you browse our website, we may also log your IP address (the internet address of your computer) to give us an idea of which part of our website you visit and how long you spend here. We do not link your IP address to any other personal information that you send to us. Like many other websites, we may use a standard technology called a "cookie" to collect information about how you use the website (see section 6\. Cookies)

Save for the use of cookies, we do not automatically log data or collect data apart from information you specifically provide to us.

>back to top

##  3\. USE OF INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We (and other KCOM Group companies) will use your information for several general purposes including: fulfilling any requests for information or services placed by you, processing any other transactions authorised by you, keeping you up to date with news about KCOM Group, our products and services, and providing other information to you which we think you may find of interest. Your personal information shall not be used for any other purposes.

>back to top

##  4\. WHO MAY PROCESS DATA

Your personal information may be processed both by us and by other companies within our Group in accordance with this privacy policy. We take all reasonable care to prevent any unauthorised access to your personal data. Personal information will not be sold or transferred to unaffiliated third parties without your prior consent.

Where any personal information is processed by us, we will comply with relevant Data Protection legislation at all times. We are registered to process data under the Data Protection Act (our registration number is D1303069) and you may refer to the Data Protection Register website for further information at [http://www.dpr.gov.uk](http://www.dpr.gov.uk/).

>back to top

##  5\. SECURITY MEASURES

We are serious about guarding the security of your personal information that we have under our control from unauthorised access, improper use and disclosure, unauthorised destruction or accidental loss. However we cannot guarantee the protection of your personal data as due to the nature of the Internet, the Website is theoretically accessible by any user of the World Wide Web. You should be aware that when you disclose personal information on the Website it may be collected by another user and may result in unsolicited messages from other Internet users.

>back to top

##  6\. COOKIES

Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information which are downloaded to your device when you visit a website. Cookies are then sent back to the originating website on each subsequent visit, or to another website that recognises that cookie.  

Cookies do lots of different jobs, like letting you navigate between pages efficiently, remembering your preferences, and generally improve user experience. They can also help to ensure that adverts you see online are more relevant to you and your interests.

You can find our more information about cookies and the cookies we use in our Cookie Use Policy.

>back to top

##  7\. ACCESS AND CHANGES TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Upon request, we may provide you with a copy of the personal information which we hold about you (in return for a small fee). Please address requests to [datacomplianceofficer@kcom.com](mailto:datacomplianceofficer@kcom.com) and insert "access request" as the subject heading, or write to us at the KCOM Group address, stating your name and email address for identification purposes.

At your request, we will use reasonable efforts to update / correct personal information previously submitted by you. You may also request that we cease processing the personal information we have about you and that we delete your personal information from our database or records. However, it may be impossible to delete your information without some residual information because of backups and records of deletions.

Please address your requests to change or delete your personal information to [info@kcom.com](mailto:info@kcom.com) and insert "change details" or "unsubscribe" as appropriate as the subject heading. Alternatively you may write to us at the KCOM Group Address, stating your name and email address for identification purposes.

We will only perform the activities outlined above to the extent that such activities will not compromise privacy or security interests.

If you do not receive a response to your enquiry – or if you feel your enquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, please contact:

The Information Commissioner  
Wycliffe House  
Water Lane  
Wilmslow  
Cheshire  
SK9 5AF

Tel: 01625 545700  
Fax: 01625 524510  
Website: [ www.ico.org.uk](http://www.ico.org.uk/)   
Email: [mail@informationgovernance@ico.org.uk](mailto:informationgovernance@ico.org.uk)

>back to top

##  8\. CHANGES TO THIS POLICY

We may change this privacy policy from time to time. When such a change is made we will post a revised version on the website. It is your responsibility to view this privacy policy from time to time to be aware of any such change. Your continued use of the website will indicate your agreement to any such change.

>back to top

##  9\. ENQUIRIES

If you have any further enquiries or concerns about our privacy policy please email us at [webprivacy@kcom.com](mailto:webprivacy@kcom.com) or write to us at the KCOM Group address.

>back to top

##  10\. MANAGING YOUR CONTACT WITH KC

If you would like to stop unsolicited telemarketing calls from KC and other companies, please contact the Telephone Preference Service on 0845 0700707 and register your telephone number(s). Direct marketing calls should stop after 28 days.

If you would like to stop unsolicited direct marketing mailers from KC and other companies, please contact the Mail Preference Service on 0845 703 4599 and ask for a registration pack. Direct marketing mailers should decrease after 3 months. (Remember to re-register if you change your address.)

If you would like KC ONLY not to call or mail you with details of products, services and special offers:

  * Residential customers please call 01482 602555.
  * Business customers please contact your Account Manager or call 01482 602900.

If you would like to stop unsolicited marketing facsimiles (faxes), please contact the Fax Preference Service on 0845 0700702 and register your fax number(s). Direct marketing faxes should stop after 28 days. If you are an individual consumer or a sole trader, it is illegal to send you such faxes unless you have given explicit permission to the sender.

>back to top

## Cookie Use Policy

##  What is a cookie?

Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information which are downloaded to your device when you visit a website. Cookies are then sent back to the originating website on each subsequent visit, or to another website that recognises that cookie. Cookies are useful because they allow a website to recognise a user’s device. You can find more information about cookies at:

[www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) and [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) .

For a video about cookies visit [www.google.co.uk/goodtoknow/data-on-the-web/cookies](http://www.google.co.uk/goodtoknow/data-on-the-web/cookies)

Cookies do lots of different jobs, like letting you navigate between pages efficiently, remembering your preferences, and generally improve user experience. They can also help to ensure that adverts you see online are more relevant to you and your interests.

The cookies used on this website have been categorised based on the categories found in the ICC UK Cookie guide. A list of all the cookies used on this website by category is set in our Table of Cookies.

Most web browser settings are set for you to accept both our cookies and third party cookies. However, you are able to adjust those settings (in relation to both our own cookies and those of third parties) to accept the cookies, to prompt you to accept or refuse a cookie each time one is sent, or to reject all cookies outright.

If you wish to reject our cookies, you can configure your browser to do so, but please be aware that if you do, certain functionality of the website may not be available and your use of the website may therefore be diminished.

You can find out how to manage cookies for your browser here <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/>

###  Social Media Buttons

In order to implement the Social Media Buttons including Twitter, Facebook and YouTube, and connect them to the relevant social networks and external sites, there are scripts from domains outside our control. You should be aware that these sites are likely to be collecting information about what you are doing all around the internet, including on our site. If you click on any of these buttons, these sites will be registering that action and may use that information. You should check the respective policies of each of these sites to see how exactly they use your information and to find out how to opt out, or delete, such information.

##  Further reading

###  Information about cookies

Useful information about cookies can be found at:

###  Internet Advertising Bureau

A guide to behavioural advertising and online privacy has been produced by the internet advertising industry which can be found at:

###  International Chamber of Commerce United Kingdom

Information on the ICC (UK) UK cookie guide can be found on the ICC website section:

<http://www.international-chamber.co.uk/our-expertise/digitaleconomy>

## Terms of use

This website (" **website** ") is owned and operated by KCOM Group PLC (" **KCOM** " or " **we** " or " **us** "). KCOM Group is a company, registered in England under number 2150618 at 37 Carr Lane, Hull HU1 3RE.

**Your use of this website will be governed by the Terms and Conditions set out below and the terms of our privacy policy ("Terms and Conditions"). Please read them carefully.**

**Where you use this website to order specific goods and services from us, additional Terms and Conditions may apply to your order. Any additional Terms and Conditions that apply will be brought to your attention when you place an order.**

We reserve the right to change these Terms and Conditions at any time without notice by posting changes on the website. It is your responsibility to familiarise yourself with the Terms and Conditions regularly to ensure that you are aware of any changes. Your use of the website after a change has been posted will signify your acceptance of the modified Terms and Conditions.

**If you do not agree with these Terms and Conditions, please do not use this website.**

**Contents**

  * 1\. INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY
  * 2\. DISCLAIMER
  * 3\. LINKS TO THIRD PARTY WEBSITES
  * 4\. COMMUNICATIONS VIA THE WEBSITE
  * 5\. CHANGES TO WEBSITE
  * 6\. ENTIRE AGREEMENT
  * 7\. SEVERANCE
  * 8\. LAW AND JURISDICTION

##  1\. INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY

**1.1 Copyright**  
All website design, text, graphics and the selection and arrangement of them are either Copyright © 2001-2005, KCOM Group PLC or its third party licensors. All rights are reserved.

**1.2 Trade Marks**  
All trading names, brand names, products and service names and titles and copyrights used in the website are trade marks, trade names and service marks or copyrights of their respective holders. No permission is given by us for their use by any person other than such holders and such use may constitute an infringement of the holders' rights.

**1.3 Restricted Use of website Content**  
Permission is granted to electronically copy or print portions of this website for your own personal, non-commercial use. Any other use of materials on this site without our prior written consent is strictly prohibited.

Back to table of contents

##  2\. DISCLAIMER

**2.1** We do not warrant that the website will be available at all times or that it is virus or error free. Whilst we make all reasonable attempts to exclude viruses from the website, we cannot ensure such exclusion and no liability is accepted for viruses. You are therefore recommended to take all appropriate safeguards before downloading information or images from the website.

**2.2** The website is for information purposes only and is provided on an "as is" basis. We accept no liability for the accuracy, completeness, currency or truth (save for fraudulent representations) of any of the information contained in the website or for any reliance placed by any person on such information. This disclaimer and exclusion of liability shall not apply to the Price Manual that we make available via the website. You shall be entitled to rely on the accuracy of the information we provided in the Price Manual at all times.

**2.3** Any advice given on this website is for guidance purposes only. Any such advice should not be relied upon or used as a substitute for legal or other professional advice on your specific requirements.

**2.4** Except as stated herein, all warranties, Terms and Conditions, whether express or implied, statutory or otherwise relating to information and material on this site or sites accessed through this site are excluded to the extent permitted by law. Any applicable warranties will be set out in our Terms and Conditions relating to the provision of our goods or services.

We will not, and our suppliers and licensors will not, be liable whether in contract, tort or otherwise for any loss or damage which:

**i.** arises other than through our negligence or the negligence of our employees, agents or contractors; or

**ii.** is not a reasonably foreseeable consequence of our negligence; or

**iii.** is any business loss including, but not limited to, loss of revenue or loss of profits, or loss of anticipated savings or wasted expense, or data being lost or harmed, or for any indirect, special or consequential loss or damage of any kind arising from access to, or any use of the information and material contained on this site, or any site you may access through this site.

We do not restrict or exclude our liability for:

**i.** personal injury or death directly caused by us or our employees whilst acting in the course of their employment with us or for fraud;

**ii.** physical damage to your personal property up to £100,000 due to any one event or series of connected events where such damage is due to our negligence or the negligence of our employees, agents or contractors acting in the course of their employment with us;

**iii.** any of our liabilities which cannot by law be excluded or restricted.

Back to table of contents

##  3\. LINKS TO THIRD PARTY WEBSITES

**3.1** Certain links on the website may lead to other websites - which are not under our control. The use of third party websites is entirely at your own risk and we accept no liability for the content of any linked site or any link contained in a linked site. Links provided on the website are provided to you only as a convenience and the inclusion of any link does not imply reliability and endorsement by us of the content of any third party's website.

**3.2** These Terms and Conditions do not apply to any third party website linked to the website. You should read the Terms and Conditions of those websites before using them and direct any questions or comments about the linked website's contents to the relevant website provider.

**3.3** You are not entitled (nor will you assist others) to set up links from your own websites to this website (whether by hypertext linking, deep-linking, framing, toggling or otherwise) without our prior written consent, which we may grant or withhold at our absolute discretion.

Back to table of contents

##  4\. COMMUNICATIONS VIA THE WEBSITE

**4.1** Where you are given the facility to enter information on to, or communicate via, the website you agree to use the website for lawful and civil purposes only and that you will not (nor allow others to):

**4.1.1** post or transit any material which is offensive, racist, abusive, indecent, defamatory, obscene or menacing;

**4.1.2** impersonate any person or entity, or falsely state or otherwise misrepresent your affiliation with any one or any entity;

**4.1.3** post or transmit any statements which are intentionally false or misleading;

**4.1.4** post or transmit any material which you do not have the right to transmit; or

**4.1.5** post or transmit any advertising, promotional materials or other forms of solicitation.

**4.2** You agree to fully and effectively indemnify us and keep us fully and effectively indemnified from and against all costs, claims, liability, expenses (including legal expenses), damages and losses incurred by us as a result of a breach by you of the provisions contained in this clause 4, whether arising under tort, statute or otherwise.

Back to table of contents

##  5\. CHANGES TO WEBSITE

We are serious about guarding the security of your personal information that we have under our control from unauthorised access, improper use and disclosure, unauthorised destruction or accidental loss. However we cannot guarantee the protection of your personal data as due to the nature of the internet, the website is theoretically accessible by any user of the World Wide Web. You should be aware that when you disclose personal information on the website it may be collected by another user and may result in unsolicited messages from other internet users.

Back to table of contents

##  6\. ENTIRE AGREEMENT

These Terms and Conditions represent the entire understanding relating to the use of the website and supersede all other statements, representations or warranties (whether written, made electronically or orally) made by us. Nothing in these Terms and Conditions shall affect the liability of either party in respect of any misrepresentation, warranty or condition that it makes fraudulently. Any rights not expressly granted in these Terms and Conditions are reserved by us.

Back to table of contents

##  7\. SEVERANCE?

If any provision of these Terms and Conditions are found to be invalid or unenforceable by a court, it will be severed from the rest of these Terms and Conditions which shall remain unaffected.

Back to table of contents

##  8\. LAW AND JURISDICTION

These Terms and Conditions will be governed by the laws of England and Wales. Disputes arising in relation to this website shall be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the Courts of England and Wales.

Back to table of contents
